PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- You may be surprised that there is such a thing
- 也许你会惊异于世界上竟然会有被称为
as a color scientist, but at Pixar,
色彩科学家的角色 但是在皮克斯
color plays a role in almost
色彩几乎在我们每次的艺术性决策中
every artistic decision that we make.
都起到了重要的作用
While this lesson will focus on the science of color,
虽然这节课关注的是色彩的科学
there is obviously a whole world of color
但很明显 艺术家们
that artists think about.
认为色彩是另一个缤纷的世界
Here we are in the color mastering suite.
我们正在一个调色室中
The equipment that we use
我们所使用的设备
is basically a supercomputer version of Photoshop,
本质上来说就是一个超大号的 Photoshop
but it kinda looks a little bit
但它看起来
like the Star Trek Enterprise.
更像是史塔克工业的产品
My goal in this lesson is to show you that
在这堂课中 我的目标就是告诉你
color is really part physics and part human perception,
色彩既包含物理学 又包含人类的感知
and at the end of this lesson,
在这堂课的结尾
you'll have a chance to manipulate the color
你将有机会操控色彩
using scenes from our films
用我们的电影中场景
to achieve various artistic goals.
达成各种艺术目标
But first we need to understand
但首先 我们要了解
how the tools in this room work.
这间房间中的工具是如何运作的
So let's go back to a simple question.
所以 我们先退回到一个简单的问题
What is color?
什么是颜色？
Color is a property of light,
颜色的光的一种属性
and light comes from light sources.
光从光源中来
And there are all different kinds of light sources.
世界上有各种各样的光源
For example, I'm currently being lit by these lamps.
举个例子 我现在就被这些灯所照亮
Without these, our scene would look very different.
没有这些灯 我们的场景看起来就非常的不同
And using a flame as our light source,
如果用火焰作为光源
like these two candles,
比如这两个蜡烛
really changes the feel of the scene.
将极大的改变场景的感觉
The light is not only dimmer,
光线不仅变得更暗了
but it emits a reddish-orange light.
而且也变得更橘红色了
Seeing this light on a white piece of paper
从一张白纸上观察这些光线
is a great way to show this.
是一种非常不错的展示方法
Try pausing this video and hold your own
试着暂停视频 用你自己的白纸
white piece of paper up to the screen beside mine.
立在屏幕前
Notice the difference between my white paper and yours.
你就会发现我的纸与你的纸之间的不同
They're not the same, right?
它们不一样 对吧？
Now compare how the same piece of paper looks
现在 对比一下同样的纸
under the most powerful light source in the solar system,
在太阳系最强光源 太阳
the sun.
照耀下的不同吧
The sun gives off really intense light,
太阳能发出非常强烈的光
especially in the middle of the day.
特别是在中午
You can clearly see that the light on this paper
你能清楚的发现照在这张纸上的光线
is much whiter than the candle light.
比烛光更白
Inside, the light was more reddish.
在室内 光线更红
So, where did the red light go?
所以 红色的光线都去哪了？
Let's go back inside so I can show you what happened.
让我们回到室内一探究竟
The key is to think of all light
其中的关键 就是认为所有的光
as a mixture of colors.
都是各种色彩的混合
Sir Isaac Newton famously demonstrated this
艾萨克·牛顿先生用他著名的
when he used a glass prism to break up sunlight.
三棱镜分光实验来展示了这一切
When sunlight passes in and out of the prism,
当阳光穿过三棱镜
it bends, or refracts,
它们弯折 或称为 折射
and splits up into a spectrum of colors.
分散为一条光谱
After Newton, other scientists discovered
在牛顿之后 其他科学家发现
that the light's wavelength is what determines
光的波长决定了
how much it will refract, and what color it will be.
它们折射的量 以及它们对应的色彩
Bluer light has a shorter wavelength and bends more.
越蓝的光具有越短的波长 也弯折得越多
Redder light, with longer wavelengths, bends less.
光线越红 波长越长 弯折得越少
And this is the key point.
这就是重中之重
Sunlight looks white
阳光之所以是白色的
because it contains all visible colors.
是因为它包含了所有可见的色彩
Scientists have developed a 2-D graph
科学家们研发了一种二维图表
to easily visualize the colors contained
用以简单地展示
in any given light source.
不同光源所包含的色彩
In this graph, along the X-axis, is the wavelength,
在这个图表中 X 轴表示波长
and along the Y-axis is the intensity of that wavelength.
Y 轴表示波长对应的强度
For example, here's the graph of what daylight looks like.
举例来说 这就是日光在图表中的样子
This is known as the spectrum of daylight.
这被称为日光的光谱
And a graph like this is called
而这种图表被称为
a spectral power distribution.
谱功率分布
And here's the spectral power distribution of candlelight.
这里是一张烛光的谱功率分布
Notice it doesn't contain the same intensity
请注意它具有不同的
of blue and green wavelengths.
绿色和蓝色波长的强度
If we shine candlelight through a prism,
如果我们让烛光通过三棱镜
we can't see a full rainbow.
我们不会得到完整的彩虹
The reds are strong,
红光部分很强烈
but the blue wavelengths are much weaker.
但蓝光波长的强度则非常的弱
Is this first exercise, you'll have a chance
在第一个练习中 你将有机会
to explore the spectrum of various light sources,
发现不同光源的光谱
and answer some questions about them.
并回答一些关于它们的问题
For example, what do you think the spectrum
比如说 你认为
of a laser would look like? aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
激光的光谱会是什么样的？ aimozhen.com/pixarinabox